We had made it to France.
The last few weeks had changed us, we were stronger, fitter, more adventurous in our flight.
Our flock was now moving in perfect synchrony, whirling in the sky and performing elaborate acrobatics.
We particularly enjoyed following coastlines where we could catch the best winds to glide over the long beaches of Brittany.
It had been a beautiful day. The sun was setting but our leaders decided to keep flying a little longer.
The evening air was clear and balmy. Darkness gradually fell upon us, and one by one, stars lit up the sky.
We were flying along majestic granite cliffs, illuminated by the moonlight. We could see our shadow cast on the white rocks.
I looked at the sky, and, suddenly Nunyati’s words came back to me.
“Never trust the moon, Mawusi. She’s a traitor. She’ll make you believe she’s your friend by lighting up your path, but a full moon will turn you into prey.”
I looked back, searching for Banjoko, and that’s when I noticed three large shadows flying behind ours.
Our leaders noticed them too. Adrenaline awoke the flock and all eighty birds sped as one body.
“Mawusi!” I heard my friend calling me. He never called me by my name; that’s how I knew he was scared.
I heard the falcons shriek too. They were close.
I panicked. I knew too well we couldn’t outdistance them.
What chance did we have, a group of tiny sand martins against three trained hunters?
Our only hope was to compete against each other. I saw my friends realised it too.
In a split second, the graceful flock was gone: all that was left was a crowd of shrieking creatures fleeing helplessly in all directions.
I decided to dive towards the ocean, hoping the falcons wouldn’t follow me.
They didn’t.
I found a small cavity at the base of the cliff, almost at sea level. I hid there.
My heart was racing, the wind was howling and the waves were crashing around me.
I could hear the helpless cries of my friends in the distance.
I stayed there until morning, shaking in the darkness, petrified.
At sunrise, I finally dared to emerge from my shelter.
I called for Banjoko, but all I could hear was my own voice echoed against the cliffs.
The falcon had gone, and I was alone.
I was completely alone.